stevensearcy

MY LIVE LinkedIn LINK

CELL (615) 992-8560 | E-MAIL stevenaaronsearcy@gmail.com

A creative and engaging Software Developer with a passion for all technology and development. Specializes in thinking creatively and maintaining a commitment to exceed expectations through the scope of teamwork. Actively pursuing opportunities to continue providing programming skills, creative techniques, and leadership ability to a fast-paced environment.

SKILLS Languages / Frameworks

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (JS), TypeScript (TS), Java, jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass, ES6, Angular JS, Angular 6, Angular Material, ReactJS, Material UI, React Native, Redux, NoSQL, MySQL, SQL server, Node, Mongodb, Express, AWS Serverless, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch Kibana, AWS Elasticsearch, GraphQL, AWS Appsync, Mocha, Jest

Technologies

Visual Studio Code, Elasticsearch, AWS Elasticsearch, DataGrip, IntelliJ, AWS Suite, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Slack, NPM, Atom, Yarn, Responsive Web Design, Dependency Injection, Android Studio, Repository Pattern, WebAPI, AJAX, JSON, XML

Other Skills (and/or currently learning)

Agile Project Management, Agile methodologies, Scrum methodologies, Unit Testing, Multitier Architecture, Salesforce, Cordova and Ionic, Docker, Seed, Stripe, Netlify, Cloudwatch, CloudFront, Route 53, Cognito, Cl SUMO Logic, Cypress Testing WordPress, Repository Pattern, UX/UI, troubleshooting with Mac OSX and Windows, Leadership, Event Management, Collaboration, Problem-solving, Detail oriented

PROJECTS

Serverless Scratch App (Personal Project)

An application that uses Serverless-Stack to create note-taking capability along with a user registration interface.

- Used Lambda & API Gateway, Dynamo DB, Cognito, S3, CloudFront, Route 53, Certificate Manager, CloudWatch, React.js, React Router, Bootstrap, Stripe, Seed, Netlify, Github and Sentry
- Login, logout, signup, post, delete, edit, administrative access, password encryption, credit card processing, backend API security, and file uploads

Bulletin Board (Personal Project)

A sleek application build that utilizes CRUD operations using front-end as well as back-end integrations in the development process.

- Used ReactJS, Webpack, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Nodemon
- Login, logout, signup, post, delete, edit, administrative access and password encryption
- CRUD operations allow users to create an account, create, edit, and delete posts

EDUCATION

Bethel School of Technology

October 2020 - July 2021

Woz U Full Stack Development program. Learned how to build robust web applications using JavaScript and React. Acquired skills to program using JS, build database-driven web applications using Node and Mongodb, and create richly interactive client-side apps using the JavaScript ReactJS library. Worked 30-60+ hours weekly on individual and team projects.

The University of Tennessee, Knoxville

August 2013 - May 2018

Bachelor of Science in Hospitality Management. Developed skills in each aspect of the hospitality industry

WORK EXPERIENCE Blackberry Farm

August 2019 - July 2020

- Served and created lifelong experiences for guests according to Blackberry Farm and Relais & Chateaux luxury resort standards
- Crafted unique and inspiring cocktails for guests under the guidance of six world-renowned sommeliers
- Worked as a brewery assistant and taproom associate at the number one rated craft brewery in Tennessee

stevensearcy

MY LIVE LinkedIn LINK

CELL (615) 992-8560 | E-MAIL stevenaaronsearcy@gmail.com

 Crafted unique and inspiring cocktails for guests under the guidance of six world-renowned sommeliers

Chick-fil-A Franchise

May 2018 - July 2019

- Learned and practiced the detail oriented skills to be successful in the Chick-fil-A culture
- Accepted into the Chick-fil-A Leadership Development Program in aspirations of becoming an owner/operator in the franchise
- Studied trends relating to product forecasts and competition in the area
- Mastered each facet of the restaurant and began leading shifts